Let us first take a look at what we mean by discrete and continuous spaces.
我们先来看看离散空间和连续空间的含义
Recall the definition of a Markov Decision Process where we assume that
回忆下马尔可夫决策流程的定义
the environment state at any time is drawn from a set of possible states.
我们假设任何时间的环境状态来自于一组潜在状态
When the set is finite,
当该组合是有限组合时
we can call it a discrete state space.
我们可以将其称之为离散状态空间
Similarly with actions, if there is a finite set of them,
动作也类似 如果有一组有限的动作
the environment is said to have a discrete action space.
则表示环境有一个离散动作空间
Having discrete spaces simplifies things for us.
离散空间简化了问题
For starters, it allows us to represent any function of
首先 使我们能够将任何状态和动作函数
states and actions as a dictionary or look-up table.
表示为字典或查询表
Consider the state value function V which
假设有一个状态值函数 V
is a mapping from the set of states to a real number.
它是从一组状态到实数的映射
If you encode states as integers,
如果将状态表示为整数
you can code up the value function as a dictionary using each state as a key.
则可以将值函数表示为字典 并将每个状态当做键
Similarly, consider the action value function Q
类似地 假设有一个动作值函数 Q
that maps every state action pair to a real number.
它将每个状态动作对映射到一个实数
Again, you could use a dictionary here or store the value function as a table or matrix,
同样 你可以使用字典或将值函数存储为表格或矩阵
where each row corresponds to a state,
每行对应一个状态
and each column to an action.
每列对应一个动作
Discreet spaces are also critical to a number of reinforcement learning algorithms.
离散空间对很多强化学习算法来说也很关键
For instance, in value iteration,
例如 在值迭代中
this internal four loop goes over each state as one by one,
这个内部 for 循环逐个遍历每个状态
and updates the corresponding value estimate V of
并更新相应的估值 V(s)
s. This is impossible if you have an infinite state space.
如果状态空间是连续的 则不可能这么操作
The loop would go on forever even for
循环将永远持续下去
discrete state spaces with a lot of states this can quickly become infeasible.
甚至对于有很多状态的离散状态空间来说 这一流程也很快变得不可行
Model-free methods like Q-learning assume discrete spaces as well.
Q 学习等不基于模型的方法也需要离散空间
Here, this max is being computed over all possible actions from
这里 我们对状态 S′ 的所有潜在动作执行 max 运算
state S prime which is easy when you have a finite set of actions.
如果有一组有限的动作 则很轻松
But this tiny step itself becomes
但是如果动作空间是连续的
a full-blown optimization problem if your action space is continuous.
这个小小的计算步骤本身就会变成完全失败的优化问题
So what do we exactly mean by continuous spaces.
那么连续空间到底是什么意思？
The term continuous is used to contrast with discrete.
连续是离散的反义词
That is a continuous space is not restricted to a set of distinct values like integers.
连续空间并不限定于一组独特的值 例如整数
Instead it can take a range of values, typically real numbers.
相反 它可以是一定范围的值 通常是实数
This means, quantities like state values that could be depicted as,
这意味着状态值等量值
say a bar chart,
例如表示离散情况的
for a discrete case,
条形图
one bar for every state,
每个状态对应一个长条
will now need to be thought of as a a density plot over a desired range.
现在需要转换成预期范围内的密度图
The same notion extends to environments where the state is no longer
同一记法也扩展到了环境中
a single real valued number but a vector of such numbers.
状态不再是单个实数 而是一个此类数字的向量
This is still referred to as a continuous space just with more than one dimension.
这样依然称之为连续空间 只是不再是一个维度
Okay, before we go any further,
在继续深入讲解之前
let's try to build some intuition for why continuous state spaces are important.
我们尝试了解下为何连续状态空间很重要
Where do they even come from?
它们来自何处？
When you consider a high-level decision making task like playing chess,
思考一个高级决策制定任务 例如下棋
you can often think of the set of possible states as discrete.
经常可以将一组潜在状态看做离散状态
What piece is in which square on the board.
每个棋子都在棋盘上的哪个方框内
You don't need to bother with precisely where
你不需要精确地确定
each piece is located within its square or which way it is facing.
每个棋子处在方框内的哪个位置或朝着哪个方向
Although these details are available for you to inspect and wonder about,
虽然你也可以了解这些细节信息
why is your knight staring at my queen.
并思考 为何你的骑士在瞪着我的王后
These things are not relevant to the problem at hand
但是这些信息与要解决的问题不相关
and you can abstract them away in your model of the game.
你可以从游戏模型中删除这些信息
In general, grid-based worlds are very popular in reinforcement learning.
通常 网格环境在强化学习中非常热门
They give you a glimpse at how agents might act in spatial environments.
它们使你能够直观地查看智能体在空间环境中的行为如何
But real physical spaces are not always neatly divided up into grids.
但是现实的物理空间并不能始终清晰地划分为网格
There is no cell 5-3 for the vacuum cleaner robot to go to.
扫地机器人无法前往单元格 (3,5)
It has to chart a course from its current position to say 2.5
它必须从当期位置绘制一条到这个点的路线
meters from the west wall by 1.8 meters from the north wall.
即距离西侧墙壁 2.5 米并且距离北侧墙壁 1.8 米
It also has to keep track of its heading and
它还需要跟踪朝向
turn smoothly to face the direction it wants to move in.
并且平滑地转向要前往的方向
These are all real numbers that the agent may need
这些都是智能体可能需要处理
to process and represent as part of the state.
并表示为状态的一部分的实数
Actions too can be continuous.
动作也可以是连续的动作
Take for example a robot that plays darts.
例如玩飞镖的机器人
It has to set the height and angle it wants to release the dart at,
它必须设置扔飞镖的高度和角度
choose an appropriate level of power with which to throw et cetera.
选择相应级别的扔力
Even small differences in these values can have
即使这些值出现小小的变化
a large impact on where the dart ultimately lands on the board.
也会对飞镖最终落在板上的位置有很大的影响
In general, most actions that need to take place
通常 需要在物理环境中
in a physical environment are continuous in nature.
采取的大多数动作本质上都是连续动作
Clearly, we need to modify our representation or
很明显 我们需要修改表示法或算法
algorithms or both to accommodate continuous spaces.
或者同时修改二者以便处理连续空间
The two main strategies we'll be looking at are
我们将讨论的两个主要策略是
Discretization and Function Approximation.
离散化和函数逼近